该放松了
翻译
零玖/presisco
校对
presisco
特效
压制
presisco
啊！这样根本不会有进展
Guh! This isn't getting us anywhere.
怎么了，“煎饺”？
What's the matter, perogie?
你累了？
You tired?
我不要疲惫，我只要结果
I don't get tired. I get results.
“拉我起来”的标志是晃一下还是晃两下？
Was the sign for "pull me up" one wiggle or two?
紫晶，保持注意力
Amethyst, stay focused.
就我们所知，青金石和碧玉的融合体
For all we know, Lapis and Jasper's fusion
可能就在眼前
could be right under our noses.
这就是我们要穿救生衣的原因
This is why we wear life jackets.
你-你还好吗？
Are -- are you all right?
什么也没有
Nothing.
哦，感觉
Oh, it feels like
我们已经搜索了好几“光年”了
we've been searching for light years.
呃，“光年”测的是光
Uh, light years measures light.
不是年
Not years.
我受够这些...“就剩尿布”了
And I'm sick of these...Life diapers.
安全不是玩笑，珍珠
Safety is no punch line, Pearl.
安全就是我们的任务
Safety is our job.
我们必须找到青金石和碧玉
We must find Jasper and Lapis.
只要还存在
As it stands,
她们的融合体就是定时炸弹
their fusion is a ticking time bomb.
青金石不会出事吧？
Is Lapis gonna be okay?
她使用能力将她们的融合体
She had control when she used her power
拖入海中时，她是清醒的
to drag their fusion into the ocean,
但是，像她们那样由猜忌和愤怒
but a fusion like theirs is unstable,
束缚在一起融合体是不稳定的
bound together by anger and mistrust.
一旦约束被打破
If that bond snaps,
她们的愤怒会彻底释放，摧毁一切
their anger will take over and destroy.
不要担心，青金石
Don't worry, Lapis.
我们不会让你和鱼群入睡的
We won't let you sleep with the fishes.
短语“sleep with fish”出自著名黑手党电影“The Godfather”（教父）
我们得继续搜索
We're gonna have to keep looking.
但首先，我们要把史蒂文带回家
But first, let's bring Steven home.
呃？蛤？
Huh? What? Wha?
不。我-我-我没事
No. I'm -- I'm -- I'm fine.
一起-一起钓鱼吧
Let's -- let's go fishing.
第一个抓到东西的获胜
First one to catch something wins.
我赢了
I win.
此处Steven的姿势致敬”Final Fantasy“（最终幻想系列）中的Cactuar（仙人掌）
我们本应在外面搜索
We should be out there searching,
而不是在这里发呆
not in here not searching.
睡眠是诅咒，一个必须承受的诅咒
Sleep is a curse, and yet a curse I need to live.
——史蒂文·宇宙
Steven Universe.
史蒂文不像我们
Steven isn't like us.
他需要休息
He needs rest.
你们就不用休息吗？
Don't you guys need rest, too?
你们看起来很疲惫
You look exhausted.
我们好极了
We look awesome.
听着，没试过
Look, you can't really knock sleep
就没有发言权
until you try it.
而且，也许我们可以搞个有趣的
And maybe we can throw a little fun into the mix
睡衣派对！
with a slumber party!
有-有趣？
F-fun?
对啊
Yeah.
我们所有人一起，安详的眯一觉
All of us together, peacefully dozing off.
就当外面没有
It'll be like there isn't
一个满是复仇念头的融合体在用仇恨煮沸大海
a vengeful fusion boiling the ocean with hatred.
史蒂文是对的
Steven's right.
你们应该呆在家休息，但我得离开
You should stay here and relax, but I'm going.
因为我永远都是放松的
'Cause I'm always relaxed.
但石榴，你不可能
But Garnet, you couldn't possibly
一个人搜索整片海洋
search the ocean by yourself.
让我-让我们帮你吧
Let me -- let us help you.
我们是一个团队
We're a team.
不用
No.
现在你们是一个团队-睡衣团队
Right now, you're a party -- a slumber party.
史蒂文，带着些宝石人上床
Steven, put these gems to bed.
不要熬夜哦
Don't stay up too late.
冰箱里有零食
There's snacks in the fridge.
再见
Bye.
现在，在开始睡衣派对之前
Now, before we get this slumber party started,
你们有人想要睡衣伙伴吗？
would either of you care for a slumber companion?
我不用
I'm good.
珍珠？
Pearl?
我不需要睡衣伙伴
I'll pass on the slumber pals.
好吧。入睡吧
Okay. Sleep it up, then.
噢，好吧
Oh, right.
这样对吗？
Is this right?
不，你得躺下
No, you should lay down.
我知道了
I get it now.
这样对吗？
Am I doing it?
呃，这比刚才好多了
Well, that's way better than before.
但，一定要保持闭眼
But close your eyes all the way.
好。好的。我在睡觉
Okay. All right. I'm sleeping now.
我在睡觉
I'm sleeping.
你睡觉时不能说话
You can't talk while you sleep.
到底怎么才能入睡？
How's this even supposed to work?
这很简单
It's easy.
你只要躺下，怎么舒服怎么来，不要乱动
You just lie down, get nice and comfy, don't move,
而且不要想任何事情
and don't think about anything.
“宇宙小子”在演播室现场观众面前实时录制
Steven Universe was filmed before a live studio audience.
格雷格说的话在美式情景喜剧片头经常使用。
石榴在梦中的表现类似“Happy Days”（欢乐时光）中的Arthur Fonzarelli（“The Fonz”）——经典的"Aaay！"入场词
哦，我的天哪，
Oh, my goodness,
康妮马上就到了
Connie's going to be here any second now.
我简直不敢相信
I can't believe it.
你的第一次校园舞会!
Your first school dance.
让我调整一下你的领带并-
Let me just fix your tie and --
别再把史蒂文当个宝宝拉
Stop fussing over Steven like a baby.
紫晶，我是怎么跟你说的
Amethyst, what did I tell you
别在屋里滑那个
about riding that thing in the house?
祝你舞会玩的愉快，伙计
Have fun at your dance, dude.
Oh! Bungacowa!
“Bungacowa！”是“Cowabunga！”的倒装词。这是美漫中一个表达兴奋的惯用语。
最初起源于漫画“Peanuts”（或叫史努比），并由”TMNT“（忍者神龟）和Bart Simpson（巴特-辛普森一家）发扬光大
紫晶，别让我抓到你！
Amethyst, I'm gonna get you!
马上，康妮
Just a second, Connie.
你绝对猜不到紫晶刚刚-蛤？
You won't believe what Amethyst just -- huh?
我能为你做什么吗？
Can I help you?
该放松了！
Chille tid.
哦，你好，石榴——嘿，史蒂文
Oh, hi, Garnet. Hey, Steven.
你今晚一定要来沙滩上
You got to come to the beach tonight.
到时会有个篝火派对哦！
There's gonna be this huge bonfire party thing.
我去不了
I can't go to that.
我要和康妮参加一个大型舞会呢
I'm going to the big dance with Connie.
喔，盛大的舞会
Wow. The big dance.
别做出格的事哦
Don't do anything I wouldn't do.
她来了！
She's here!
好啦，我准备好去跳舞了，康-
Okay, I'm ready for the big dance con--
呃？
huh?
青金石？
Lapis?
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
Ah! Ugh!
哦，妈呀...
Oh, man...
我睡着了，然后做了个奇怪的梦
I feel asleep and had this weird dream.
我打开门，青金石在门外，然后-
I opened the door and Lapis was there, and --
呃，这听起来毫无逻辑
well, that doesn't make any sense.
青金石正和碧玉在海底融合在一起
Lapis is fused with Jasper at the bottom of the ocean.
你从没做过梦吧？
You've never had a dream before, huh?
哦...我觉得没有
Uh...I don't think so.
好吧，珍珠，梦并不总是合理的
Well, Pearl, dreams don't always make sense.
当你作梦时，你脑中的想法
When you dream, the thoughts in your head
混合在一起，组成一部诡异的影片
get all mixed up into a weird movie.
并且它们很难解释，
And they're really hard to explain,
让其看起来很无聊
which is why they're boring to listen to.
就像，有一次，
Like.this one time,
我做了个梦，好像，有些东西
I had a dream where, like, these things
挂在甜甜圈店里出售，对吧？
were being sold at the big donut, right?
但是甜甜圈店的前门
But the front door of the big donut shop
却连接到了我爸面包车的后面
led to the back of my dad's van.
于是，我走进了面包车，
So, I go into the van,
然后狮子因为某些原因在开车，但...
and Lion is driving for some reason, but...
...他开得非常好
...he's driving really well.
然后-然后我对他说，我说，“狮子-”
And -- and then I say to him, I says, "Lion --"
“狮子，你是怎么学会开面-面包车的？”
"Lion, how did you learn to drive you a v-van?
”你甚至不能“
You can't even...
“你...你都不能给我...我的...”
You...You can't bring...Me...My...
Whoo!
此处史蒂文用背上的螺旋桨飞行的画面致敬“Karlsson on the Roof”（屋顶上的小飞人）中的“Karlsson”（卡尔松）。“Karlsson on the Roof”是一部由瑞典作家Astrid Lindgren创作的儿童系列读物
狗升机！
Dogcopter!
先生，我是您最忠实的粉丝之一！
Mr. copter, sir, I'm one of your biggest fans!
求求你能给我个签名吗？
Can I please have your autograph?
狗升机先生，求求您-嘿，等等我！
Mr. copter, please -- hey, wait!
您要去哪？
Where are you going?
我希望小报中有关狗升机先生的流言
I hope the rumors about dogcopter in the tabloids
都不是真的
aren't true.
嗯？哦，嘿，珍珠！
Huh? Oh, hey, Pearl!
等等...别吃我啊！
Wait...Don't eat me!
噗！唔！哦，天哪
Ptoo! Ooh! Oh, man.
谢谢你给的升级组件，珍珠！
Thanks for the upgrade, Pearl!
这个很明显了，”Astro Boy“（铁臂阿童木）
现在我能追上狗-
Now I can catch up with dog--
喔，紫晶？
whoa. Amethyst?
Hmm.
这一切，真的开始变得诡异了
This is getting really weird.
这确实很诡异
This is weird.
嘿，那声音听起来很像-
Hey, that sounds a lot like --
史蒂文！
Steven!
青金石！
Lapis Lazuli!
史蒂文，你-你在这干什么？
Steven, wh-what are you doing in here?
呃，我知道这听起来很怪，但我正在做梦，
Uh, I know it's weird, but I'm just dreaming,
所以不用担心
so don't even worry about it.
什么？不！
What? No!
史蒂文，我正试着集中注意力
Steven, I'm trying to concentrate.
你怎么会在这里？
How are you here?
哦，我的天哪，你还好吗？
Oh, my gosh. Are you okay?
史蒂文，求求你，我-
Steven, please, I --
呃...青金石！
Ugh...  Lapis!
紫晶？
Amethyst?
嘿，你在笑什么？
Hey, what are you laughing at?
噢，罗丝！这真是太好了！
Oh, Rose! This is wonderful!
跟你在一起非常开心，罗丝！
I'm just having so much fun spending time with you, Rose!
这个太明显了，”Titanic“（泰坦尼克号）中Jack和Rose（啧啧）在船首的镜头
忘了格雷格吧，我们一起在银河系旅游！
Forget about Greg. Let's go travel the galaxy!
珍珠，非常感谢你...
Pearl, thank you so much...
修好我的车！
For fixing my van!
详见第一季第27集
哦！啊！
Oh! Ugh!
呕...
Blegh...
恶...
Gah!
珍珠？
Pearl?
呃...好的，史蒂文？
Uh... Yes, Steven?
我又做了，一个有关青金石的梦
I had another dream about Lapis.
噢...没什么！梦不是真实的！
Oh...That's okay! Dreams aren't real!
那只是拼接电影！
They're just mixed-up movies!
但我-我觉得我当时在和她对话
But I -- I think I was talking to her.
等等，你怎么知道的？
Wait. How do you know?
我不知道，但我能感觉到
I don't, but I could just feel it.
她在喊叫
She was yelling,
并且她真的受到刺激了
and she was really freaked out.
她说了什么？她还能控制住吗？
What did she say? Is she still in control?
我...我不知道
I...I don't know.
史蒂文，你刚才可能通过你的梦境
Steven, you could be using your dreams
与她进行了心灵感应
to connect with her mentally.
你能再做一次吗？
Can you do it again?
也许青金石刚好能告诉你她们在哪
Maybe Lapis can just tell you where they are.
我猜我又得入睡了
I guess I have to go back to sleep.
快，珍珠，告诉我你的梦
Quick, Pearl, tell me about your dream
帮我入睡
so I can fall asleep.
我-我的梦？
M-my dream?
来啊，珍珠！这是为了大局！
Come on, Pearl! It's for the greater good!
如果我必须的话
If I must.
好吧，在我的梦里，我正-
So, in my dream, I was --
哦？
What?
Wow!
他这就睡着了
He been sleep.
噢！我知道这已经是梦了
Oh! I know this is a dream now,
那么我能想象出任何我想要的
so I can imagine anything I want.
呃...土豆泥
Uh...Mashed potato.
Hmm.
现在，我该怎么找到青金石？
Now how do I find Lapis?
不是青金石
Not Lapis.
不是青金石～
不是青金石-
Not Lapis.
呃！狮子？
Ugh! Lion?
等等，你不是狮子
Wait. You're not Lion.
Whoa!
Aah! Ugh!
嗷，这是什么地方？
Ow. What is this place?
青金石！
Lapis!
史蒂文！
Steven!
你为什么总是-跑回来?!
Why do you keep coming back?
此处青金石与碧玉被链条连接在一起的设定致敬”Jojo's Bizarre Adventure“（Jojo奇幻大冒险）中的Chain Necklace Deathmatch（项链死斗）
我不能被分心！
I can't get distracted!
我-我得把我们困在海底
I-I've got to hold us down
借助你的星球的-海洋-的重量
with the weight of your planet's ocean.
我-必须-将她...
I've got to keep her...
等等，青金石，告诉我你们在哪
Wait, Lapis, tell me where you are.
我们能帮你
We can help you.
我告诉过你！不！
I told you! No!
Aah!
是你！！！
You!
碧玉！
Jasper!
是你！！！
You!
你-你！
You! You!
Gaah!
噢！不！！！！！
Ohh! No!
青金石！
Lapis!
你看不出来吗？
Can't you see?
我不能停下来，哪怕一秒也不行
I can't stop, not for a second.
不要再找我了
Don't look for me.
我不想要你的帮助。但-
I don't want your help. B-but --
就让我为你做这些吧！
just let me do this for you!
青金石...不！
Lapis... No!
我不再是...青金石了
I'm not Lapis anymore.
有没有感觉此处像是“Naruto”（火影忍者）漫画与动画中的Zetsu（绝）吗？
我们现在是，孔雀石
We're Malachite now.
青金石，不！
Lapis, no!
Oooragh!
快走！
Go!
青金石！
Lapis!
史蒂文，没事了，我们就在这
Steven, it's okay. We're here.
你看到她了吗？
Did you see her?
是的，她还在融合体中
Yeah. She's still fused.
而且她还能控制住，但我不知道还能坚持多久
And she's still in control, but I don't know for how long.
并且-
And --
这，真是个奇怪的派对
This is a weird party.
石榴！
Garnet! Mm.
史蒂文，你还没睡着
Steven, you're still awake.
紫晶刚才在滑滑板
Amethyst was on a skateboard.
接着狗升机对着我“喵”了一下
And then dogcopter meowed at me
而且对我说的没有任何兴趣！
and was just not interested in what I had to say at all!
也许我有些问题需要解决...
And I might have some issues I need to work out...
但青金石，她就在外面，而且他仍然-
But Lapis, she's out there, and she's still --
嘘～嘘～嘘～嘘——
shh, shh, shh, shh.
我知道你很担心，
I know you're worried,
但现在我们什么也做不了
but there's nothing we can do right now.
所以让我们放松一下
So let's take it easy.
我来告诉你们该怎么做
I'll show you how it's done.
这还真有说服力啊
That's pretty convincing.
石榴？
Garnet?
如果我可以做到
♪ If I could begin to be
你对我期望的一半
♪ half of what you think of me
我愿意做任何事
♪ I could do about anything
我愿学会像你一样，去爱
♪ I could even learn how to love like you ♪